Jen-Chieh Shen

Email: jenchieh94@gmail.com Website: www.jcs-profile.com

ABOUT

I am a well-rounded software engineer/architect expert on tool invention and comprehensive automation, currently focusing on backend infrastructure. My previous education as a game programmer gave me solid programming knowledge regarding creating things from scratch. e.g. Graphic Rendering, UI systems, Scripting Engine, Networking, etc.

KNOWLEDGE AND SKILLS

- · Designing system architecture.
- Analyzing, troubleshooting, optimizing systems.
- Business analysis, requirement analysis.
- Linux administration, maintenance, automation.
- Technical writing.
- Languages: English, Chinese.

TOOLS AND TECHNOLOGIES (SAMPLED)

- Languages: C, C++, C#, Java, JavaScript, Elisp, Python, Lua, Rust...
- Database: PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB...
- Web/network frameworks: Netty, MINA, Express.js, ws, DRF...
- Infrastructure: AWS, Digital Ocean, Docker...
- Tools: Emacs, Vim, Git, Perforce, Jenkins...

WORK EXPERIENCE

Unity Developer (Contract)

Apr., 2020 - May, 2022

Novaby - Seattle, Washington, United States

- Provide full UI elements for already built Augmented Reality application.
 - Communicate and work with upstream software engineer for two ends integration.
 - Analyze and consult CEO and her clients for making technical decisions.
 - Build framework/tools to increase productivity by maximum 80 percents

Senior Unity Engineer

May, 2020 – Jan, 2021

ultragbye - Taipei, Taiwan

- Provide full application interaction, network interface/module and tool programming.
- Create a mini/test server using NodeJS for standardized the web server side API content.
- Manage to create bluetooth connection from Mono C# to each mobile platforms and implements to Linux Kernel (Debian) using Raspberry Pi as peripheral device.

Server Software Engineer

Sep, 2018 – May, 2019

T-Nexus - San Francisco Bay Area

- Provide login server web API using Express.js in the Node JS environment.
- Design schema for the login server using mongoose built on top of the MongoDB.
- Build automated program to run the server on to the AWS using shell script.
- Install and setup Node JS environment on AWS EC2 instance running on Ubuntu.
- Communicate with client engineers to implement HTTP request model to the client using Unity C#.

OTHER EXPERIENCE

Games presented in Game Developer Conferences (GDC)

GDC at San Francisco Bay Area

GDC 2015

- "Archers Duel" two player fighting game.
- "Cardinal" visual novel game.

GDC 2017

• "Might & Blade" – Diablo like action RPG.

GDC 2018

• "Sugar Sleuths" – players discover clues to uncover who stole the camp's Master Stash of candy.

Games presented in E3 College Game Competition

Hosted by Entertainment Software Association (ESA), USA

E3 CGC 2018

• "Sugar Sleuths" - has been selected to represent our school Academy of Art University

EDUCATION

Academy of Art University, San Francisco, CA

Bachelor of Fine Arts - BFA, Game Development

Sep, 2012 - Dec, 2017